# ANDIKA PUTRA GUMILANG

<u>Jakarta, Indonesia</u> | (+62)8211 0065 957 | andikapg19@gmail.com |



### **ABOUT**

Having Over then 5 years of dedication in Sales Management, Planning, Analyst, and Operation.

A Data Analyst & Data Science Enthusiast. Highly passionate about numbers and statistics, have some experience partaking in several analytical competitions at Kaggle, and recently won 1<sup>st</sup> place for best final project in Full-Stack Data Analytics Bootcamp. I have a strong belief that when you want something, all the universe conspires in helping you to achieve it.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

### PT. GOTO (GOJEK TOKOPEDIA)

### **Account Manager Supervisor GOFOOD (November 2020 – Present)**

Developing strategies to maximize business potential, Providing imperative discussion with GOFOOD merchant Owners to increase their income by using GOJEK products, Maintaining 10 Billion GOFOOD sales/ month, and Sustaining relationships with 1.000 outlets, and in addition, I am also creating and maintaining sales dashboard performance for South Jakarta using Google BigQuery and Google Data Studio

### PT. AMERTA INDAH OTSUKA (POCARI SWEAT)

### Head Of Area (June 2017 - October 2020)

Responsible for operational and sales activity, including distribution products to all channels (General Trade and Modern Trade), Maintaining sales growth, Doing marketing activity, Sustaining strong relationships with the top 50 outlets, and Ensuring relations for business interest between PT. Amerta Indah Otsuka and Distributor are well intertwined. There were some area that I have handled, South East Sulawesi Province, South Sulawesi Province and Aceh Province, Maintain 1 main distributor with average sales 1–3.5Billion with 2-8 sub-distributor, managing 2 Supervisor sales, and 5-12 Sales team. And having 1.000-4.000 Outlet each Area.

### **Management Trainee (October 2016 – August 2017)**

A program designed to provide people with the knowledge and abilities necessary to hold a managerial position

Starting from becoming "Assistant Sales" that assigned to helping sales in performing duties, then "Sales" that assigned to maintaining sales performance in area, and Distributing products to 500 outlets, after that "Sales Supervisor" assigned to Managing 3 sales team and 3 assistant sales having around 1.500 outlets, and lastly "Internal Auditor" that assigned to Analyzing & Observing system internal to ensure the system run well and effectively. My initiative in Internal Auditor was created a distribution map to maintain distribution density

### **ORGANIZATION & PROJECT**

### Head of Sales Department Youth Speak Summit – AIESEC 2016

AIESEC is The organization focuses on empowering young people with leadership development to make a progressive social impact, approximately AIESEC have 40,000 members in 120+ countries. This was the main event of YouthSpeak forum that held in 11 big cities all over Indonesia, A Conferences with a Grand Theme of Mobilizing Indonesia Youth toward Sustainable Development Goals which is initiated by the United Nations. With the assistance of 5 team members, I was in charge of financial support in terms of sponsorship and partnership.

### Head of Marketing Department Festival Olahraga dan Seni (FORSI) UNPAD 2014-2015

FORSI is the biggest event at Padjadjaran University, 16 faculty and more than 10.000 people get involved in this event. I was in charge of financial support in terms of sponsorship and partnership and handled 20 team members that were divided into 3 divisions, Successfully We got more than 200millions cash from companies (200% vs Target), provided FREE Guest Stars, got more than 30 Media Partners, And more than 50 Entrepreneurs(tenants) involved in this event.

# **EDUCATION**

## • UNIVERSITY OF PADJADJARAN (2011-2016)

Bachelor of Geological Engineering (GPA 3.32)

### • REVOU (2022)

Full Stack Data Analyst – A Data Analyst Bootcamp with instructors from top startup companies, Designed to build experience and portfolio with extensive hands-on exercises, regular assessments, and portfolio-worthy projects by working with real clients.

### **ACHIEVEMENT**

- 1<sup>ST</sup> Best Final Group Project Full Stack Data Analyst REVOU (2022) (I Became Project Leader)
- 3<sup>rd</sup> Best Graduate of Sales Development Program PT. Amerta Indah Otsuka Batch 10
- Education Scholarship From INDOSAT (2010-2015)

## **ADDITIONAL**

# Technical Knowledge

Statistics

Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing Cluster Analysis, Customer Segmentation

Regression, Forecasting, Correlation

Data Visualization & Communication

# Language Proficiency

TOEFL (515), Bahasa Indonesia

# Tools

Spreadsheet/Excel

Python language (Google Colab, Jupiter Notebook, Visual Studio Code) Tableau

SQL language (MySQL, Google BigQuery, POPSQL)

Google Data Studio

Google Analytics

### Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andika-gumilang-6aa09b113

## Portfolio :

https://pgandika.github.io/Andika\_Gumilang\_Portfolio